He!
In 2002, my dad
had a stroke for the first time,
and he fell into the rooftop shaft.
And then,
he was heavily injured in an operation.
And later,
the sudden passing of his apprentice
exacerbated his condition.
Two years ago, he went into retirement.
Out of nowhere, he received
something left behind by his apprentice.
Perhaps it triggered something in him.
His condition acted up, and he fainted.
In his mind, his apprentice never died.
He merely went to Beijing
to teach for 12 years.
Whenever his apprentice appeared,
he'd convince him to stay
to help him investigate cases.
It seems like his memory is stuck in 2002.
I waited for you for five years!
Why didn't you save me?
Why?
Come back.
I'm waiting for you. Come down.
Keep me company. You…
Doctor.
Doctor!
He. You're awake.
Why am I here?
You fell into the rooftop shaft yesterday.
Fortunately, no bone fractures.
Just some cuts.
Fortunately?
Officer He,
you fell because you had a stroke,
and you lost consciousness.
I checked your medical records.
Your cholesterol, blood sugar,
and blood pressure levels
are dangerously high.
Did you take medication regularly?
Taking pills during all three of my meals?
Who can live like that?
Listen.
Your condition is serious.
You have to take your medication.
Otherwise, this will happen again,
-and it will be more serious.
-Okay.
There are no other huge issues,
but you will stay here for a few days.
Thanks, Doctor.
Captain Feng just left.
He told me everything.
Are you intending
to take full responsibility?
Did you tell Captain Feng
that you want to go to Beijing to teach?
He.
I'd like to apologize to you.
It's my fault.
Whether it's the missing persons case
or the homicide,
I shouldn't have brought
my emotions into the case.
Give me your hand.
-That hand.
-Why?
Press this.
He, what are you doing?
What about your IV drip?
Now is not the time to lie down.
Let's go. We have a case to crack.
Come.
In the June 30th case,
Song Qingsong is undeniably
the main suspect.
But he allegedly fled
to the US five years ago.
Immigrating is suspicious enough.
Back then, Song Qingsong
hired someone to commit a murder.
But he was acquitted
due to a lack of evidence.
We could only charge him with bribery.
Even then, it wasn't that serious.
He would get five years in jail at most.
And when he would be released,
he would still be the same old him.
The factory, the car,
and the property would still be his.
So why did he flee?
I did investigate him.
Song Qingsong had dealings in both
legitimate and illegitimate channels.
He's definitely not a good person,
but he's kind to his factory workers.
Those workers have worked
for him for more than a decade.
Oh. He also has a son
who was only three years old when he fled.
So there's probably another story
behind his hiring of the hitman.
The most effective way
to investigate Song Qingsong
is through Wu Shanlong.
But after he took over the cement factory,
he accrued debts
and is now in hiding.
Turn right at the intersection in front.
We're not returning to the station?
Shouldn't we find Wu Shanlong?
HONGYUN HUIHUANG CLUB
Who are you?
This is the dressing room.
Are you new here?
I'm Wu. W-U.
Shanlong is my name.
I am the biggest shareholder of this club.
Qingsong Cement Factory. Ever heard of it?
It's mine too.
Perhaps I could book all of you today,
so that you can get some good rest.
Hi, Mei.
-Hi, Mei.
Hi.
Come out here.
Leeching off this place every day.
Do I owe you anything or what?
Did I hear that correctly?
Do you even know who you're talking to?
Wu Shanlong.
From now on,
I won't lend a single cent to you.
Zhao Hongmei. I see you've grown arrogant.
Without me,
you would still have been the owner
of that small massage parlor.
Who gave you your first fortune?
It was me, Wu Shanlong. It was me.
Without me, this place would still
be called Dahuihuang.
You helped me?
Do you even have the wits for it?
Without me,
Song Qingsong would still
be running the cement factory,
-and you would still be his chauffeur.
-What did you say?
-I gave you your share of the money.
-Say that again.
I gave you your share of the money.
You are just incompetent.
The cement factory was a gold mine,
but you messed it up.
And now, you're leeching off me.
I've treated you with enough generosity.
Am I the shareholder here or not?
I can come and go whenever I want.
Of course. Come whenever you want.
But before you come,
clean up the mess you made.
What mess?
Tell me. What mess?
Still playing dumb?
The police just released a statement.
Xu Zhihong's body was found in Yuanlongli.
They are investigating it everywhere now.
You killed Xu Meng too.
You are now a murderer.
Why don't you learn
from your brother-in-law?
Just run away. Run.
When you're gone, everyone will be safe.
The girls under me?
I can't guarantee
they are as loyal as I am.
If one of them gets drunk
and runs their mouth,
I won't be able to stop them.
Sure.
I can run away.
But I need you to give me some money.
Are you crazy?
Zhao Hongmei.
You're talking to a murderer now.
How many lives do you risk by defying me?
Defying you? What about that?
What about that?
I won't comply, so kill me now.
Do you want to see
if I will go to the police right now?
Please be patient, sir.
Our manager is having a meeting. You…
What a coincidence.
My two old friends are here.
Great. Let's hang out.
Officer He. Officer Ran. You're here.
I was just reminiscing
about the past with Mr. Wu here.
We talked about you two.
-Speak of the devil, really.
-Is that so?
-Zhang!
-Yes?
How is the speaker outside going?
-It's almost done, Mei.
-Show me.
I have work to do. Mr. Hu,
entertain our old friends here, will you?
I'll count on you. Take a seat.
Order anything you want. Take a seat.
Take a seat.
Officer Ran!
You're more handsome than before.
Speak.
Tell us about Xu Meng and her father.
What are you on about, Officer He?
I don't know them.
Wu Shanlong,
between us, there's no need to play coy.
Back then, Song Qingsong hired a hitman
to kill Xu Meng and her father.
You did it, didn't you?
How did Xu Zhihong die?
Where is Xu Meng? Is she dead or alive?
Speak!
I'll speak. Officer He,
I'll tell you everything.
I'll come clean.
Song Qingsong gave me 40,000 yuan
to get rid of Xu Meng and her father.
He doesn't care about laws, but I do.
I paid you to get rid of them,
and what did you do?
I asked you to do it yourself,
but you paid someone else
to do it instead.
That deal could have cost me my life.
I wouldn't have done it,
even if he had punched me to death.
What about Wolfie?
You know him very well, don't you?
Get rid of them.
What? What wolf?
I don't know him.
Sure.
You said it had nothing to do with you.
Then tell me.
How did Xu Zhihong die?
Based on my understanding
of Song Qingsong,
he must have hired someone else to do it.
Achieve his goals at all costs.
That's his personality.
Why must Song Qingsong
get rid of Xu Meng and her father?
I know why.
Back then, Xu Meng
saw the tender document
inside Song Qingsong's briefcase
in the foot massage parlor.
Then, she wrote to Song Qingsong
to extort money.
Song Qingsong was furious
and wanted her gone.
Getting rid of her father
was just an afterthought.
Why didn't you tell us back then?
Because he was my brother-in-law.
But now, it's different.
Just ask me whatever you want to know.
I'll tell you everything I know.
Wu Shanlong.
Have you contacted
Song Qingsong in recent years?
We lost contact five years ago.
I don't know where he's hiding now.
Sir,
if he contacts me,
I promise to contact
the police right away.
Wu Shanlong. Do not leave Weiyang.
We will talk to you anytime.
Sure, sir. I won't leave.
Drop by when you're free.
HONGYUN HUIHUANG CLUB
That liar.
Not a word of truth from his mouth.
I made sure to ask him about Wolfie,
and his eyes looked to the right.
He knows that we don't have evidence,
and we can't do anything about him.
Now that the lead
on Song Qingsong is stuck,
we can only find
another breakthrough in the scene.
He.
I want to go through
the suspicious residents
in Yuanlongli again.
You still want to head to Yuanlongli?
What if you're stuck in there?
He.
Have you heard
of the Eye of the Vortex Theory?
What?
The eye of the vortex
is the center of the vortex.
To see it,
you must venture into the vortex.
New York Block
is at the center of the crime,
the eye of the vortex.
Residents might come and go,
but as long as the building's there,
we will find useful leads.
What?
You almost had it there.
I thought you had lost your mind.
LIANG JUAN
Yes, Officer Liang?
Okay. Got it.
What's wrong?
The Forensic Department
said they found toxins
in Xu Zhihong's skull.
-What kind of toxin?
-They are analyzing it.
Let's do it this way.
We'll split up and search.
You'll head to Yuanlongli.
I'll head to the station
to ask Liang for more information.
Okay.
Oh.
If you're taking the same route,
can you pick Xiaohe up for me at school?
I've been busy lately.
I haven't seen her in a week.
Are you and your wife…
Don't be nosy. Just do your work.
I'LL PICK XIAOHE UP TODAY
SEND MESSAGE
DATE, TIME, VIEW OPTIONS
RECIPIENT: YUN
I BOUGHT FISH TODAY
WILL YOU BE HOME FOR DINNER TODAY?
DATE, TIME, VIEW OPTIONS
RECIPIENT: YUN
TOMORROW IS THE PARENT-TEACHER DAY
WHO'S GOING? YOU OR ME?
WEIYANG NO. 1 MIDDLE SCHOOL
I like your palm.
Show me your right palm.
Xiaohe.
Uncle Ran.
My uncle came to pick me up.
I have to go now. Bye!
-Uncle Ran.
-Long time no see.
Are you here for a case?
Your dad asked me to pick you up.
Oh.
He finally remembers he has a daughter.
Come on. He has a business trip this week.
You have changed your style.
People change.
I was too childish.
It's not too late to grow up now.
Put your legs down. It's dangerous.
Tomorrow, June 8th,
our national team in Group C
will face the strongest opponent
in the group,
the Brazil team,
who is highly anticipated
to win the World Cup.
Let's hope that at 7:30 p.m. tomorrow,
our national team can create a miracle.
There's only one way to find out.
Passion
Fighting for the glory of the team
Come on, come on
Power
We will never bow under the sky
Raise your hand
Passion
Fighting for the glory of the team
Raise your hand
Power
This is not the way back to my home.
Are you trying to kidnap me?
Don't worry.
No one wants to kidnap
a wild brat like you unless
there's something wrong with their brain.
Why did you stop singing?
Oh, no. It's Friday today.
Uncle Ran, can you drive me
to the band's rehearsal?
They are waiting for me.
No. I promised He to take you home.
After that, I have a case to investigate.
Are you going to Yuanlongli?
It's on the way.
Liang. What did you find in his skull?
We found excessive arsenic
in Xu Zhihong's skull.
He was fed poison
for a long time before he died.
It might be trisenox.
Trisenox?
Arsenic, basically.
CONCLUSION: EXCESSIVE ARSENIC
FOUND IN THE VICTIM'S SKULL
Xiaohe. Slow down. Wait for me.
UNDERGROUND CAR PARK
Uncle Ran.
Are you investigating the skull?
How did you know?
Everyone in the underground scene knows.
I knew you were involved in this case.
You guys rehearse down here?
Yes. What's so shocking about that?
Many Western bands began in the garage.
What role do you play in your band?
Lead vocal and bassist.
Oh.
I also write songs. I just wrote one.
Uncle Ran, quick.
The acoustics in this spot are good.
Our keyboardist found it.
Guys, I'm here.
DO NOT THROW ANYTHING INSIDE
DO NOT TRESPASS
Uncle Ran. Just investigate your case.
I'll head back once the rehearsal is over.
I'll pick you up after two hours.
Hi, Officer Ran.
You're…
The keyboardist I told you about.
You don't recognize me? I live upstairs.
You chased after me back then.
Little boy, your wounds are…
I fell when he chased after me.
Oh, it's you.
He might look fragile,
but he can man up if need be.
He risked his life
and took these instruments
out of his dad's bar.
They call me the instrument sponsor.
GENERAL WARD
Ms. Wang.
Officer He.
Did Han Zi'ang say anything?
He woke up just now.
But no matter what the doctor or I said,
he wouldn't react to us.
The doctor said he had…
Post-traumatic stress disorder?
Yes.
Madam Wang. Calm down now.
Han Zi'ang encountered a traumatic event.
His mind and his body
need time to recover.
We're running out of time, Officer He.
The school called me.
They will release
his expulsion notice tomorrow.
-Officer He. I'm begging you.
-Please.
Get up now. I'll call the principal now.
Yesterday, several parents
escalated the issue to the board meeting.
The school is under immense pressure.
Besides, the police didn't make
any meaningful progress.
Principal Qin, I understand
the difficulty of your position.
Han Zi'ang just woke up now.
I will uncover the truth
as soon as possible.
Then, the criminal department
will release a statement.
Officer He, can you give me a deadline?
Not too long.
I need to justify myself
before the board and the parents.
Seven days. Just seven days.
Mister. Hello.
Have you seen the child in this photo?
No.
Hi, mister.
Have you seen the child in this photo?
Not at all.
Hi.
Have you seen this child?
No.
Hi. Have you seen this child?
Mr. He.
Qiao.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to see a doctor.
How do you feel now?
You introduced the doctor to Xiaohe?
She could've told me earlier.
Wait.
You're still so young.
What are you doing here?
I'm working for the Redevelopment Bureau,
and I have to talk to residents
who refuse to move.
It's stressful.
I have no one to talk to,
so I come here to talk to my therapist.
Have you not found a partner
after all these years?
I'm not in a rush.
Having a partner is nice,
but I can't find anyone as sweet
as Ran anymore.
Qiao.
We can't just live in the past.
We have to move on.
Officer Ran. Sorry for the long wait.
I have the name list
of all residents who lived
in New York Block in 1997.
-Take a look.
-Thank you so much, Ma Qiang.
Don't mention it.
Let me know if you need help.
1997 YUANLONGLI HOUSEOWNERS
TENANTS REGISTRATION FORM
Officer Ran.
After I entered through the gate,
I saw a familiar silhouette
and thought it was you.
Turns out I am right.
It's been so long.
How have you been?
Yes.
All of us have been busy in recent years.
I enrolled in the adult classes
of Weiyang University,
and I graduated last year.
What are you working as right now?
I am now interning
in an insurance company.
You encouraged me
to be more confident
and to make more friends.
And I did make more friends
and met my neighbors.
The rumors about me have stopped.
That's great.
Thank you.
You… You're injured.
You didn't even treat your injuries.
Just some cuts. It's nothing.
That's no good.
CASUAL SNEAKERS
You're being reckless.
Wounds are no joking matter.
Come.
Do you remember?
When we first met,
it was you who treated my wounds.
Yes.
I was quite clumsy back then.
Unlike you.
Actually,
my first job was a carer.
I worked in this apartment.
Ma Qiang told me before.
You cared for an old man.
Yes.
Oh.
Why did you come to Weiyang
from Guangxi? For work?
When I was little, my parents split up.
My dad moved abroad with my sister,
and I lived with my mom in Guangxi.
But after a few years,
my mom passed away due to an illness.
I had learned some nursing skills
in my night school,
so I asked my relatives to get me a job.
That was how I came to Yuanlongli.
When the old man
passed away due to an accident,
I had nowhere else to go.
So, I continued to rent this place.
It must have been tough on you
surviving on your own.
But no need to carry everything
on your shoulders.
If you need help,
just come to me.
Don't worry.
The toughest part has already passed.
I'm seeing the silver lining now.
But…
Yes?
DAJIANCHANG NEIGHBORHOOD
After the incident on the rooftop,
I always feel that someone
is staring at me at midnight.
It's creepy.
Qiao. If you run into trouble,
just call me.
Thank you, Officer Ran.
You're welcome.
Give me a moment.
Qing.
Qing. A thief broke in again.
What about your place?
-Exactly. Did you lose anything?
-That guy again?
Yes.
What's wrong?
Oh, your hidden boyfriend.
Why didn't you tell us?
No. Don't say that.
This is Ran Fangxu. Officer Ran.
He's here to investigate.
Mr. Officer, there's a pervert
in this building.
We live in Unit 1713.
Our clothes that we hung to dry
and our shoes were all stolen by a thief.
I reported it to the management,
but Qian Dajun doesn't care at all.
Also, that pervert also stole lingerie.
-Disgusting!
-That's right.
Mr. Officer, you must intervene.
Don't worry.
I'll investigate this properly.
No need to investigate.
We all know who the pervert is.
-Yes. We know.
-That's right.
Speak.
Why do you stare at the unit
belonging to the Xus?
I… No, I didn't do that.
I didn't do that.
You didn't?
Let's speak at the police station then.
Come.
I'll come clean.
I did do it.
Someone paid me to do it.
In the summer of 1996,
someone paid me 500 yuan
to spy on the unit opposite.
He told me to call him
if I found anything unusual.
You've been spying on them
for six years just for 500 yuan?
A work accident left me handicapped.
And I'm divorced.
I live all alone in this apartment.
I need something to entertain myself.
Speak.
Who hired you?
What's his name? What does he look like?
It was a man.
I don't know his name.
He looked like he was around 25 years old.
He was tall and bespectacled.
He had a 30/70 side part,
and he looked like a gentleman.
What a jerk.
I won't forgive you.